Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree:





IT Management Professional, Software Engineering Manager, Complete SDLC exposure. E-commerce, Banking and Public sector domains.



Current Designation: Software Engineering Manager

Current Company: renowned US Based Sports goods and

Bicycle Brand

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: Gurgaon, Delhi / NCR, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: java, j2ee, spring, hybris, agile methodology, project management, scrum master, software engineering manager,confluence,jira,splunk,dynatrace,microsoft azure,kanban,scrum,people management,business analysis,vendor

management, Techno Functional

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

Summary

Software engineering manager with around 10+ years of extensive experience on Hybris and java technology in Banking and E-Commerce domain. Currently working with a renowned US based Sports goods brand for their in house development team, previously worked with Sapient Nitro, Accenture for a UK Banking Giant, Barclays. Have worked in onshore offshore model and also have experience of working at Client location at Manchester, UK.

Work Experience

renowned US Based Sports goods and Bicycle Brand as Software Engineering Manager Aug 2017 to Till Date

Software Engineering manager managing team of developers, Testers and Business Analysts. Exposure in Vendor Selection and Management.

Sapient Nitro as Track Lead Jun 2015 to Jul 2017

Tech Mahindra Limited as Senior Software Engineer Aug 2014 to Jun 2015

Accenture Services Private Limited as Software Engineering Analyst May 2010 to Aug 2014

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University (GGSIU) in 2009

PG: from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University (GGSIU) in 0

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

SCJP / OCJP 1.6 (Oracle Certified Java Programmer)

Banking Generalist Certification from Massachusetts Institute of Technology

hybris

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JAVA	8	2019	10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
IT MANAGEMENT		2019	11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
CONFLUENCE		2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
BUSINESS ANALYSIS		2017	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
AGILE		2019	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Scrum Master		2019	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
IT Project Management		2019	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SPLUNK		2019	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Spring		2019	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Hibernate		2017	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
HYBRIS	6.7	2020	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Hindi	Expert			
English	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Hybris Based project Client: renowned US based Organisation

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2017 - Mar 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: hybris/ java

Project Title: Hybris Based Project

Client: Sapient Nitro

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2015 - Jul 2017 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Hybris/ Java

Project Title: Java Based Project

Client: TechMahindra

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Sep 2014 - May 2015 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite 1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=675ec3e7841dd52319e7eb4e6bed2310585b5f5018400012041615095...

Project Details: Government client

Project Title: Customer gateway

Client: Barclays Bank

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: May 2010 - Sep 2014
Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: banking application

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full time